Des Gouttes & Associés



Prof. Dr. Jean-Paul Vulliéty

Senior Counsel
Attorney at Law
Full professor of business law, University of Geneva

Languages

English, (Swiss-)German, French, Norwegian

Contact Details

Telephone: + 41 22 704 30 50 jpvulliety@desgouttes.ch

Expertise

Corporate and Contracts

Jean-Paul Vulliéty has an extensive experience advising clients in international commercial transactions, subject to Swiss law, foreign laws or international conventions (e.g. the Vienna Convention on Sale of Goods), particularly sales, mandate and service agreements, agency, distribution, license, franchising, shareholder and joint venture agreements. He has frequently acted as lead counsel in complex acquisition operations.

Litigation and Arbitration

Jean-Paul Vulliéty has also been involved in more than 80 international and domestic commercial arbitration proceedings, as counsel or arbitrator (sole arbitrator, co-arbitrator, or chairman), under all the main rules of international arbitration.

His expertise in corporate and commercial law matters and dispute resolution encompasses a wide range of sectors, including life sciences and biotechnology, pharmaceutical, luxury goods, transport (aviation and rail), energy (particularly oil & gas), commodities, construction and infrastructure projects and real estate transactions.

Over the years, Jean-Paul Vulliéty has held several academic positions, namely at the University of

Education

1998	University of Geneva, Doctor degree
	(PhD), summa cum laude, Geneva
	University
1987	Admission to the Geneva Bar
1978-1986	Law degree (licence en droit), Master
	degree in law, and pre-doctoral studies,
	University of Geneva

Professional Experience

Since 2023	Senior Counsel, Des Gouttes & Associés
Since 1998	Full professor of business law, University of Geneva (law of obligations, contract law, international transactions, construction contracts)
1998-2023	Partner, Lalive (Geneva)
1998-2007	Visiting Professor, Université Catholique de Louvain (Belgium)
1993-1998	Partner, Berger Recordon de Saugy (Geneva)
1987-1993	Associate, Berger Recordon de Saugy (Geneva)

Des Gouttes & Associés

Geneva since 1998 where he is currently a full professor in charge of the chair of Business law of the Geneva University School of Economics and Management (GSEM). He contributed to the creation of the Geneva University Master of International Trading, of which he has been the academic director for more than ten years. Together with his university colleagues Prof. Marie-Noëlle Zen-Ruffinen and Prof. Gilbert Probst, he co-founded the Swiss Board Institute, which has become over the years, through its Journée du Conseil d'Administration, a leading platform in Switzerland for members of company boards.

Jean-Paul Vulliéty is the author of numerous scientific publications in the field of business law and business transactions. He is one of the regular contributors to the major commentaries of Swiss business and contract law. He is the drafter for the WTO/UNCTAD of several model agreements for business transactions.

Other Activities

0. 0014	
Since 2014	Member of the Institute of World's
	Business law of the ICC, Paris
Since 2011	Co-Founder and Board member of the
	Swiss Board Institute (SBI), Geneva
Since 2007	Member of the ICC Commission on
	Commercial Law and Practice (CLP)
Since 2007	Co-Founder and Academic Director of
	the Geneva University Master's
	Program in Commodity Trading
Since 2007	Member of the Board and then
	President (since 2013) of the
	Arab-Swiss Chamber of Commerce
2008-2023	Member and then President (since
	2014) of the Civil law Commission of
	the Geneva Bar Association
2009-2020	Vice-Chair and then President (since
	2014) of the International Sales
	Commission of the Union
	Internationale des Avocats

Memberships

Geneva Bar Association (OdA - former President of the Civil law Commission), Swiss Bar Association (SAV), Arbitration Association Swiss (ASA), Europe-Latin-American Arbitration (ELArb - Member of the Executive Committee), Union Internationale des Avocats (UIA - former President of the International Sales Commission), Swiss Association of Competition Law, Groupe de Travail Contrats Internationaux (GTCI)